Ben Shaktman Papers
Ben Shaktman Papers
- Correspondence Subject Files
  - Nazareth, Jeanine and Vasca, 1975-1979 (Box 19)
  - Neijna, Barbara, 1994-1996 (Box 19)
  - Neipris-Wille, Janet, 1982 (Box 19)
  - New Federal Theatre, 1982 (Box 19)
  - New York Public Library, 1977 (Box 19)
  - Newberry, Greg, 1995 (Box 19)
  - Newman, Danny, 1977; 1982 (Box 19)
  - Nimoy, Leonard, 1972-2002 (Box 19)
  - Noel, Craig, 1971-1973 (Box 20)
  - Noonan, John Ford, 1972 (Box 20)
  - North Shore Music Theatre, See Slane, Stephen.
  - Norton, Elliot, 1971; 1982 (Box 20)
  - Nugent-Head, Marie, 1975-2007, undated; 3 folders of 4 (Box 20)
  - 1975-2007, undated, 1 folder of 4 (Box 21)
  - Nussbaum, Susan, 1992-1993; 1982 (Box 21)
  - O-PA (Box 21)
  - Oates, Joyce Carol, 1973 (Box 21)
  - Obadiah, Rick, 1982 (Box 21)
  - O'Bannon, Helen, 1976; 1979 (Box 21)
  - Oberlin Music Theater, 1970 (Box 21)
  - Obolensky, Kira, 1996-1997 (Box 21)
  - O'Casey, Eileen, 1982 (Box 21)
  - O'Casey, Sean, See O'Casey, Eileen.
  - Ojai Music Festival, 2007 (Box 21)
  - Olivier, Laurence, 1976 (Box 21)
  - O'Neill, Carlotta Monterey, 1964-1965 (Box 21)
  - Padula, Edward, 1966 (Box 21)
  - Pagano, Richard and L.M., 1982-2005 (Box 21)
  - Pagano Casting, 1996
    - Administrative (Box 21)
    - "Chicago Hope" (Box 21)
    - "Internal Affairs" (Box 21)
    - "Picket Fences" (Box 21)
    - "Rakes Progress" (Box 21)
    - "Where's Marlowe?" (Box 21)
  - Passeltiner, Bernie, 1976 (Box 22)
  - Pasternak's "Thinking Like A Director" Workshop, 1994 (Box 22)
  - Pawley, Barbara, 1996 (Box 22)
  - PE-Q (Box 22)
  - Peabody (MA) High School, 1990; 1995,; 2004 (Box 22)
  - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, 1975 (Box 22)
  - Perkins, Grant, 1997-2005 (Box 22)
  - Philippe, Gillieron, 1999 (Box 22)
  - Pierson, Jon, 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - Piskor, Frank, 1963-1975 (Box 22)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1974-2004; 4 folders of 13 (Box 22)
  - 1974-2004, 4 folders of 13 (Box 23)
  - 1974-2004, 5 folders of 13 (Box 24)
  - Pittsburgh Public Theater photographs (Oversize 1)
  - Poitier, Sidney, 1962 (Box 25)
  - Polis, Joel, 1978-1979 (Box 25)
  - Pons, Beatrice Moore, 1971 (Box 25)
  - Posvar, Wesley, 1977-1980 (Box 25)
  - P.O.V., 1993 (Box 25)
  - Preston, Carol, 1975-1977 (Box 25)
  - Prince, Harold, 1964-1965; 1975-1976 (Box 25)
  - The Pythons, 1983 (Box 25)
  - Quen, Jacques M., 1971-1974 (Box 25)
  - R-RI (Box 25)
  - Raphael, Esther, 1964-1975 (Box 25)
  - Raphael, Lisa, 1982-2007; undated; 3 folders of 5 (Box 25)
  - 1982-2007, undated; 2 folders of 5 (Box 26)
  - Rappaport, Ruth, 1995; 2003,; 2005 (Box 26)
  - Rawson, Chris, 1994-1996 (Box 26)
  - Rayvid, Jay, 1976; 1981 (Box 26)
  - Rea, Edith, 1975 (Box 26)
  - Reidenbaugh, Gerald F., 1962-1963 (Box 26)
  - Rich, Christine, 1990 (Box 26)
  - Rich, David Lowell, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Ridley, Clifford A., 1973 (Box 26)
  - Rieck, Margaret, 1975-2000; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - RO-RY (Box 27)
  - Robbins, Jerome, 1965-1966 (Box 27)
  - Rochestie, Sally Jo, 1994 (Box 27)
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1983; 1985,; 1987 (Box 27)
  - Roenly (?), Lynn, 1985-1986 (Box 27)
  - Rogers, Fred and Joan, 1975-1981; 2003 (Box 27)
  - Rosenak, David, 1995 (Box 27)
  - Rosenblatt, Suzanne, 2005-2006 (Box 27)
  - Rosenberg, Claire, 1989-1993 (Box 27)
  - Ruscio, Michael, 1993 (Box 27)
  - Russell, Cathy, 1992-1995 (Box 27)
  - Ryan, Michael S., 1996 (Box 27)
  - Ryback, Ronnie, 1984-1985 (Box 27)
  - S-SC (Box 27)
  - St Ivany, Andra, undated (Box 27)
  - Sandy-Bedino, Joyce, 1967-1991 (Box 27)
  - Sanfield, Steven, 1975; 1980,; 1991-1999 (Box 27)
  - Santa Fe Film Workshops, 1994 (Box 27)
  - Santa Monica Bay Towers, 1996 (Box 27)
  - Schell, Ina, 1973 (Box 27)
  - Schneider, Alan, 1980-1981 (Box 27)
  - Schneider, Eugenie ("Jean"), 1983-2005 (Box 27)
  - Schoenfeld, Gerald, 1982; 1997 (Box 28)
  - Schreiber, Terry, 1979-1999 (Box 28)
  - Schulberg, Sandra, 1981-1982 (Box 28)
  - Scott, Rina, 1990-2006 (Box 28)
  - SE-SM (Box 28)
  - Seidner, Harold, 1979-1980; 1992-2000 (Box 28)
  - Sexton, Anne, 1965-1974; 1982 (Box 28)
  - The Sexton Company, See Sileika, Gintare.
  - Shaktman, Esther, See Raphael, Esther.
  - Shaktman, Lewis, 1995-2005 (Box 28)
  - Shaktman, Lizzie, 1970 (Box 28)
  - Shaktman Family miscellaneous, 1968-1998 (Box 28)
  - Shapiro, Aaron, 1968-1999 (Box 28)
  - Shaw, Roy, 1994 (Box 28)
  - Shayne, Alan, See Warner Brothers Studio.
  - Sileika, Gintare, 1980-1981 (Box 28)
  - Silverman, Fred, 1970 (Box 28)
  - Singleton, Margeaux, 1982-1987 (Box 28)
  - Sioux, Sarah, 1999-2002 (Box 28)
  - Skinner, Jeane, 1994 (Box 28)
  - Slane, Stephen, 1971-2002 (Box 29)
  - SN-SZ (Box 29)
  - Snow, Anne, 1998-2008 (Box 29)
  - Soble, Lisa-Marie, See Pagano, Richard and L.M..
  - Society of Stage Directors and Choreographers, 1964-1981 (Box 29)
  - Solvang, Tobi, 1996 (Box 29)
  - Sondheim, Stephen, 1976; 1994 (Box 29)
  - Speers, Thelma, 1973- 1990 (Box 29)
  - Stellar, Grace, John and Pat, 1997-2002 (Box 29)
  - Stern David, 1967-2006; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Stern, Diane, 1968-2006; undated; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Stern, Lois Shaktman, 1960-2002; 3 folders of 6 (Box 30)
  - 1960-2002, 3 folders of 6 (Box 31)
  - Strauch, Barbara, 2000 (Box 3`)
  - Strickland, William E., Jr., 1977-1978 (Box 31)
  - Strouse, Charles, 1968-1978 (Box 31)
  - Sundance Institute Independent Producers Conference, 1994; 1 folder of 2 (Box 31)
  - 1994, 1 folder of 2 (Box 32)
  - 1995 (Box 32)
  - Swartz, Nellie Lou, 1975-1978 (Box 32)
  - Swoyer, Julia, 1977; 1983 (Box 32)
  - Syracuse University, 1963-2005 (Box 32)
  - T-TH (Box 32)
  - Tagg, Alan, 1978-1982 (Box 32)
  - Teitel, Carol, 1976-1982 (Box 32)
  - Thompson, Michael, 1976-1978 (Box 32)
  - Thornburgh, Richard, 1978 (Box 32)
  - TI-U (Box 32)
  - Toser, David, 1974-1985 (Box 32)
  - Tutera, Cindy, 1977-1993 (Box 32)
  - UCLA School of Theater Film and Television, 1997 (Box 33)
  - UCLA Workshops, 1993 (Box 33)
  - Universal City Studios, 1972-1975 (Box 33)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1975-1981 (Box 33)
  - V-WE (Box 33)
  - Van Scoten, Neil, 1990-2000 (Box 33)
  - Vestoff, Virginia, 1973-1982 (Box 33)
  - Wakefield, Yanoulla, 1983-1987 (Box 33)
  - Waley, Arthur, 1963 (Box 33)
  - Wanamaker, Sam, 1960 (Box 34)
  - Warner Brothers Studio, 1973; 1979-1985 (Box 34)
  - WARP, See Obadiah, Rick.
  - Watson, Doug, undated (Box 34)
  - Weil, Marian J., 1982; 1986 (Box 34)
  - Weiswiller, Carole, 1998 (Box 34)
    See also "The Human Voice".
  - Weitzman, Lew, 1973-1983 (Box 34)
  - Wells, Wendy, 1967; 1985-1988 (Box 34)
  - Wesker, Arnold, 1974-2003; 4 folders (Box 34)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Annie Wobbler", 1984 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Caritas", 1992 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Catching Up With Wesker", 2003 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Chips With Everything", 1997 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Denial", 1997 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Four Portraits Of Mothers", undated (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "The Kitchen", 1987 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Letter To A Daughter", 1991 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Shylock", 1989 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Their Very Own And Golden City", 1980 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Three Women Talking" (working title), undated (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Toys" (provisional title), 1985 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Whatever Happened to Betty Lemon?", 1986 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Wild Spring", 1992 (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Arnold "Yard Sale", undated (Box 35)
  - Wesker, Daniel, 1988-1994 (Box 36)
  - Wesker, Dusty, 1985-2007; 3 folders (Box 36)
  - Wesker, Lindsay, 1985-2005 (Box 36)
  - Wexler, Connie and Peter, 1979-1994 (Box 36)
  - "White Mile" Workshop, 1994 (Box 36)
  - Wilcox, Kay, 1976; 1982-1983 (Box 37)
  - Wilder, Isabel, 1966 (Box 37)
  - Wilson, Rhonda, 1994 (Box 37)
  - Wilt, Robert D., 1972 (Box 37)
  - Wolff, Wendy, 1974 (Box 37)
  - Wolfson, Barbara, 1977-1979 (Box 37)
  - Williams, Elaine, 1979; 1985,; 1990 (Box 37)
  - Wolsk, Eugene V., 1966; 1979 (Box 37)
  - Wood, Audrey, 1966; 1974-1975 (Box 37)
  - Yale University, 1962; 1967,; 1975,; 1984 (Box 37)
  - Zabusky, Charlotte Fox, 1982 (Box 37)
  - Zacky, Dolores, 1995 (Box 37)
  - Zeisler, Peter, 1962-2005 (Box 37)
  - Zimmerman, Paul, 1994 (Box 37)
  - Zulia, Ernest, 1996 (Box 37)
  - miscellaneous, partial name:
    - A-P, 5 folders (Box 38)
    - R-Z, unsigned, 4 folders (Box 39)
- Productions directed by Shaktman
  - "Annabelle Broom, The Unhappy Witch" Charles Playhouse, 1965 (Box 40)
  - "The Balcony" Charles Playhouse, 1966
    - Reviews (Box 40)
  - "Balyashnikov" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1977-1978
    - Music (Box 40)
    - Notes (Box 40)
    - Photographs (Box 40)
    - Programs (Box 40)
    - Reviews (Box 40)
    - Script, 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Set design (Box 40)
  - "The Beggar's Opera" Syracuse University, 1963
    - Director's report (Box 40)
    - Photographs (Box 40)
    - Production book (Box 40)
    - Publicity (Box 40)
    - Research and notes (Box 40)
    - Reviews (Box 40)
  - "The Blood Knot" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1978
    - Audio tape (Box 40)
    - Notes (Box 40)
    - Programs (Box 40)
    - Props (Box 40)
    - Publicity (Box 40)
    - Reviews (Box 40)
    - Schedules (Box 40)
    - Script (Box 40)
    - Set design (Box 40)
  - "Cabaret" Cape Cod Melody Tent, 1970
    - Notes (Box 41)
    - Programs (Box 41)
    - Reviews (Box 41)
    - Script (Box 41)
  - "The Cave Dwellers" George Washington University, 1962 (Box 41)
  - "Death of a Salesman" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981
    - Audio tapes (Box 41)
    - Costumes (Box 41)
    - Notes (Box 41)
    - Production book (Box 41)
    - Programs (Box 41)
    - Publicity (Box 41)
    - Reviews (Box 41)
    - Set design (Box 41)
  - "Diplomatic Relations" Cape Playhouse, 1965
    - Notes (Box 41)
    - Production book (Box 41)
    - Reviews (Box 41)
    - Script (with revisions) (Box 41)
  - "A Doll's House" North Shore Music Theater, 1973
    - Correspondence (Box 41)
    - Notes (Box 41)
    - Script, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Set design (Box 41)
  - "Emmet Sez" The Marsh Theater, 1996
    - Correspondence (Box 41)
    - Costume sketches (Box 41)
    - Notes (Box 41)
    - Publicity (Box 41)
    - Reviews (Box 41)
  - "The Emperor Jones" Charles Playhouse, 1964
    - Correspondence (Box 41)
    - Costume sketches (Map-case 110)
    - Production book (Box 41)
    - Reviews (Box 41)
  - "Faces of Love" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1978-1979
    - Audio tapes (Box 41)
    - Production book (Box 41)
    - Programs (Box 41)
    - Reviews (Box 41)
    - Script (Box 41)
  - "Fiddler On The Roof" North Shore Music Theater, 1971
    - Casting (Box 42)
    - Clippings and reviews (Box 42)
    - Correspondence (Box 42)
    - Notes (Box 42)
    - Photographs (Box 42)
    - Production book, 3 folders (Box 42)
    - Programs (Box 42)
    - Reviews (Box 42)
    - Schedule (Box 42)
    - Vocal score (Box 42)
  - "Finishing Touches" Royal Poinciana Playhouse, 1974
    - Files (Box 42)
    - Programs (Box 42)
    - Reviews (Box 42)
    - Script (Box 42)
    - Set design (Box 42)
  - "The Glass Menagerie" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1975
    - Correspondence (Box 42)
    - Photographs (Box 42)
    - Production book (Box 42)
    - Programs (Box 42)
    - Publicity (Box 42)
    - Reviews (Box 42)
  - "Good Day"/"The Exhaustion Of Our Son's Love" Cherry Lane Theatre, 1965
    - Reviews (Box 42)
  - "The Guns of Carrar" Syracuse University, 1963
    - Correspondence (Box 42)
    - Drafts (Box 42)
    - Photographs (Box 42)
    - Photographs, oversize (Oversize 1)
    - Production book (Box 42)
    - Poster (Box 42)
    - Programs (Box 42)
    - Reviews (Box 42)
    - Script (Box 42)
  - Henry V, See "King Henry V".
  - "The Importance of Being Earnest" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1978-1979
    - Audio tapes (Box 43)
    - Costumes (Box 43)
    - Notes (Box 43)
    - Production book (Box 43)
    - Programs (Box 43)
    - Props (Box 43)
    - Publicity (Box 43)
    - Reviews (Box 43)
    - Schedules (Box 43)
    - Scripts (Box 43)
    - Set design (Box 43)
  - "Jack and Jill" City Theatre Pittsburgh, 1996
    - Casting (Box 43)
    - Correspondence (Box 43)
  - "A Joyful Noise", 1966
    - Audiorecording, Joyful Noise I, shaktman_001; 1 reel, 7 1/2 ips, running time 9:25 (Box 43)
    - Audiorecording, Joyful Noise II, shaktman_002; 1 reel, 7 1/2 ips, running time 34:16 (Box 43)
    - Casting (Box 43)
    - Correspondence (Box 43)
    - Notes (Box 43)
    - Outlines (Box 43)
    - Photographs (Box 43)
    - Programs (Box 43)
    - Research (Box 43)
    - Reviews (Box 43)
    - Revisions (Box 43)
    - Rewrites, 4 folders (Box 43)
    - Script (Box 43)
  - "King Henry V" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1976-1977
    - Notes (Box 44)
    - Production book (Box 44)
    - Programs (Box 44)
    - Publicity (Box 44)
    - Reviews (Box 44)
    - Script (Box 44)
    - Set design (Box 44)
  - "King Lear" North Shore Music Theater, 1973
    - Casting (Box 44)
    - Character notes (Box 44)
    - Clippings and reviews (Box 44)
    - Correspondence (Box 44)
    - Costumes (Box 44)
    - Music and sound effects (Box 44)
    - Photographs (Box 44)
    - Production book, 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Programs (Box 44)
    - Rehearsal schedules (Box 44)
    - Research (Box 44)
    - Set design (Box 44)
    - Text prosody (Box 44)
  - "Macbeth" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980
    - Audio tapes (Box 44)
    - Casting (Box 44)
    - Costumes (Oversize 2)
    - Music (Box 44)
    - Notes (Box 44)
    - Production book (Box 44)
    - Programs (Box 44)
    - Publicity (Box 44)
    - Reviews (Box 44)
    - Script (Box 44)
    - Set design (Box 44)
  - "The Man in the Glass Booth" Old Globe Theater, 1971
    - Correspondence (Box 44)
    - Notes (Box 44)
    - Photographs (Box 44)
    - Programs (Box 44)
    - Publicity (Box 44)
    - Production book (Box 44)
    - Research (Box 44)
    - Reviews (Box 45)
    - Scripts (Box 45)
    - Set design (Box 45)
  - "The Motel Plays" H B Playwrights Foundation, 1997
    - Correspondence (Box 45)
    - Programs and flyers (Box 45)
    - Research and notes (Box 45)
    - Scripts (Box 45)
  - "New Morning For The World", 1982-1983
    - Clippings and reviews (Box 45)
    - Correspondence (Box 45)
    - Programs (Box 45)
    - Research and notes (Box 45)
  - "Of Mice and Men" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1978
    - Costumes (Box 45)
    - Music (Box 45)
    - Notes (Box 45)
    - Photographs (Box 45)
    - Production book (Box 45)
    - Programs (Box 45)
    - Publicity (Box 45)
    - Reviews (Box 45)
    - Schedules (Box 45)
    - Script (Box 45)
    - Set design (Box 45)
  - "The Old Ones" The Lambs, 1974
    - Audio tapes (Box 45)
    - Casting (Box 45)
    - Correspondence (Box 45)
    - Costs (Box 45)
    - Costumes (Box 45)
    - Legal (Box 46)
    - Music (Box 46)
    - Production book, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Publicity (Box 46)
    - Reviews (Box 46)
    - Scenery (Box 46)
    - Script, 2 folders (Box 46)
    - Script galleys (Box 46)
    - Stage manager's book (Box 46)
  - "Politics and Poker" Charles Playhouse, undated
    - Notes (Box 46)
    - Production book (Box 46)
  - "Poppy" Charles Palyhouse, 1964
    - Photographs (Box 46)
  - "She Loves Me" Charles Playhouse, 1964
    - Notes (Box 46)
    - Poster (Box 46)
    - Production book (Box 46)
    - Program (Box 46)
    - Reviews (Box 46)
    - Set design (Box 46)
  - "Shelton Maine" InterACTivity Festival, 1996 (Box 46)
  - "Square in the Eye (Let's Face It)" Establishment Theatre, 1965
    - Correspondence (Box 46)
    - Production book (Box 46)
    - Notes (Box 46)
    - Reviews and clippings (Box 46)
    - Script (Box 46)
  - "Tangles" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981
    - Notes (Box 47)
    - Production book, 2 folders (Box 47)
    - Publicity (Box 47)
    - Script, 4 folders (Box 47)
    - Set design (Box 47)
    - Programs (Box 47)
    - Reviews (Box 47)
  - "Three Sisters" Syracuse University, 1963
    - Notes (Box 47)
    - Photographs (Box 47)
    - Printed material (Box 47)
    - Production book (Box 47)
    - Script (Box 47)
  - "Tom Sawyer" Charles Playhouse, 1964
    - Costume design (Box 47)
    - Notes (Box 47)
    - Production book (Box 47)
  - "Twelfth Night" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1975
    - Costumes (Box 48)
    - Photographs, 3 folders (Box 48)
    - Production book (Box 48)
    - Programs (Box 48)
    - Props (Box 48)
    - Publicity (Box 48)
    - Reviews (Box 48)
    - Set design (Box 48)
  - "Uncle Vanya" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1976
    - Notes (Box 48)
    - Production book (Box 48)
    - Programs (Box 48)
    - Pronunciation guide (Box 48)
    - Reviews (Box 48)
    - Set design (Box 48)
    - Script (Box 48)
  - "Voices" Trinity Church, 1970
    - Auditions (Box 48)
    - Libretto (Box 48)
    - Music (Oversize 1)
- Productions involving Shaktman
  - "Betrayal" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 49)
  - "Buried Child" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 49)
  - "Campaign Relief" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 49)
  - "The City Girls", undated; 2 folders (Box 49)
  - "The Desert" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 49)
  - "Father's Day" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1977 (Box 49)
  - "For Colored Girls Who Have Considered Suicide…" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1979 (Box 49)
  - "Home" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1982 (Box 49)
  - "I'm Getting My Act Together and Taking It On The Road" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 49)
  - "James Joyce's Women" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 49)
  - "Juno and the Paycock" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 49)
  - "Krapp's Last Tape/Act Witout Words II/Come and Go" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1979 (Box 49)
  - "The Life Of Galileo" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 49)
  - "Loot" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 49)
  - "A Midsummer Night's Dream" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1982 (Box 49)
  - "Mister Roberts" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1979 (Box 49)
  - "One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1975 (Box 49)
  - "Saint Mark's Gospel" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 49)
  - "The Seagull" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1979 (Box 49)
  - "Sizwe Bansi Is Dead" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1976 (Box 49)
  - "Sleight Of Hand" Piyysburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 49)
  - "Slow Dance On The Killing Ground/Medal Of Honor Rag" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1978 (Box 49)
  - Streetsongs" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 49)
  - "Tartuffe" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1982 (Box 49)
  - "Terra Nova" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 49)
  - "Tintypes" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1982 (Box 49)
  - "Two Gentlemen Of Verona" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 50)
  - "Vanities and Ashes" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1979 (Box 50)
  - "You Know Al, He's A Funny Guy" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1981 (Box 50)
  - "You Never Can Tell" Pittsburgh Public Theater
    - Costume design for character Gloria, played by Erica Peterson, Pittsburgh Public Theatre 3rd season, 1977-1978; Artist/mark: David Toser, '77; 28 x 50.6 (Map-case 110)
    - Miscellaneous material, 1979 (Box 50)
- Productions proposed by Shaktman
  - "The Cherry Orchard", 1980 (Box 50)
  - "Emigrants", undated (Box 50)
  - "The Four Seasons", 1988 (Box 50)
  - "Golden Boy", 1981 (Box 50)
  - "Goose Amid the Revolt", 1994 (Box 50)
  - "Hart Songs":, 1996 (Box 50)
    - Audio tapes, 2 folders (Box 50)
    - Correspondence (Box 50)
    - Sheet music (Box 50)
  - "He Who Gets Slapped", 1967 (Box 50)
  - "In White America", 1996 (Box 50)
  - "Letter To A Daughter", 1979-1980 (Box 50)
  - "Major Barbara", 1965 (Box 50)
  - "The Man in the Glass Booth" Film remake, 1996 (Box 50)
  - "Orlando", undated (Box 50)
  - "Private Eyes" Odyssey Theater Ensemble, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 50)
  - "The Resistable Rise of Arturo Ui" Village Version, 1964
    - Notes (Box 50)
    - Research (Box 50)
    - Script (Box 50)
  - "Take It From Me", 1966 (Box 50)
  - "Thornton Wilder Tribute", 1966 (Box 50)
  - "Try Try Again", 1966 (Box 50)
- Writings
  - Adaptations of others' work
    - "The Human Voice", 1994-1998 (Box 51)
      - Copyright (Box 51)
      - Correspondence (Box 51)
      - Research and notes (Box 51)
      - Scripts (Box 51)
    - "Little Orphan Annie", 1966 (Box 51)
    - "Marjorie Morningstar", 1968 (Box 51)
    - "Once Upon a Time", See "Balyashnikov".
    - "Song in the Theatre", 1960 (Box 51)
      - Correspondence (Box 51)
      - Production notes (Box 51)
      - Scripts and sheet music (Box 51)
  - Articles and essays
    - "Aryan Corn", 1982 (Box 51)
    - "Association of Producing Artists", 1962 (Box 51)
    - "Brecht on Broadway", 1962 (Box 51)
    - "Letter From New York", 1961 (Box 51)
    - "Society of Space", 1963 (Box 51)
    - "Talks With Mrs. Berthold Brecht", 1962 (Box 51)
  - Books
    - Use a Mirror, 1968 (Box 51)
  - Lectures and courses
    - "Activity for Progress" Syracuse University, 1963 (Box 51)
    - Chinese Drama, 1962 (Box 51)
    - "Drama 62" Syracuse University, 1963 (Box 51)
    - "Great Playwriting" New York University, undated (Box 51)
    - IBM Seminars, 1968-1969; 4 folders (Box 51)
    - "Makers of Modern Drama" New York University, undated (Box 52)
    - Performing Arts Course California Institute of the Arts, 1990 (Box 52)
    - "Play Production" Syracuse University, 1962 (Box 52)
    - "Repertory Theater", undated (Box 52)
    - "The Social Consciousness of an Artist", 1966 (Box 52)
    - "Social Science 300", undated (Box 52)
    - "Theater" Syracuse University, 1965 (Box 52)
    - "Writing for the Theatre" New york University, 1966 (Box 52)
  - Letters to the editor
    - On death of Bernie Jacobs, 1996 (Box 52)
  - Lyrics
    - "Village Idiot", 2000 (Box 52)
  - Pamphlets
    - "PPT's Building Program" Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1980 (Box 52)
  - Personal journals, 1967-2006; 4 folders (Box 52)
  - Plays
    - "Communism Now", 1989 (Box 52)
      - Clippings (Oversize 1)
      - Correspondence (Box 52)
      - Proposal packets, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Research and notes (Box 52)
    - "Frances", 1961 (Box 52)
    - In The Words of the Faithful, See "Communism Now".
    - "Judge/Jazz":, 1985-1990
      - Correspondence (Box 52)
      - Drafts, 2 folders (Box 52)
      - Research notes (Box 53)
      - Scripts, 5 folders (Box 53)
    - "Let There Be Voices", 1958 (Box 53)
    - "The Living Stage" Charles Playhouse, 1964 (Box 53)
    - "Lucretia", 1973 (Box 53)
    - "Point in the Square", 1960 (Box 53)
    - "Puss in Boots":, 1965
      - Drafts (Box 53)
      - Notes and revisions (Box 53)
    - "Spain 1937", 1963
      - Correspondence (Box 53)
      - Draft (Box 53)
      - Production book (Box 53)
      - Research and notes (Box 53)
    - "The Waiting Room", 1970
  - Poetry, 1959; 1971,; 1973,; undated (Box 53)
  - Program notes
    - Pittsburgh Public Theater, 1975-1982 (Box 53)
  - Reviews
    - "The Deer Park", 1967 (Box 53)
    - "Inadmissable Evidence", 1965 (Box 53)
    - "The Mating Dance", 1965 (Box 53)
    - "Postmark Zero", 1965 (Box 53)
    - "Solo recital by Daniel Nagrin", 1966 (Box 53)
    - "To The Actor", 1985 (Box 53)
    - fragments and notes, 1966 (Box 53)
  - Screenplays
    - "The Arnold Idea", 1993 (Box 53)
    - "Ask Me, I'll Tell You How I Feel" for Marcus Welby, M.D., 1972 (Box 53)
    - "Away For The Weekend", undated (Box 53)
    - "The Builders", 1972 (Box 53)
    - "Campaign Relief", 1983 (Box 54)
      - Copyright (Box 54)
      - Correspondence (Box 54)
      - Drafts (Box 54)
      - Pittsburgh Public Theater production (Box 54)
      - Research (Box 54)
      - TV proposals (Box 54)
    - "Father To My Father", 1972 (Box 54)
    - "The Frozen Boy" for Hill Street Blues, 1984
      - Drafts (Box 54)
      - Research and notes (Box 54)
      - Script (Box 54)
    - "The Glory Club", 1972 (Box 54)
    - "Hands", 1972 (Box 54)
    - "In My Father's House", 1972-1974
      - CBS contract (Box 54)
      - Correspondence (Box 54)
      - Drafts (Box 54)